# Harshita Sharma

Github Profile: harshita-sharma011/oep-e2e, harshita-sharma012 | LinkedIn: harshita-sharma1729

## **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with experience in Cloud Native mainly Orchestration - Kubernetes, Containerization - Docker and Cloud-native Storage Solution - OpenEBS.

Deployed and managed Cloud Native Applications on GKE using Dynamically Provisioned Container Attached Storage, integrated and tested on Gitlab pipelines using Chaos Engineering Tools written in Ansible, Python and Golang and ran as Kubernetes Jobs and Monitored using Prometheus.

Using Automation on every stage of Product Lifecycle and provisioning PAAS services, GKE clusters, Data Migration.

Open Source Event Speaker at FOSDEM Brussels, CNCF meetups and Cloud Native Rejekts on topics like Local PV, VMware Velero Backup/Restore, Data Migration, ZFS.

Skilled in Python, Kubernetes, Golang, Ansible, GitHub, Linux.

# **EXPERIENCE**

Mayadata, Bengaluru - Software Engineer

Mar 2019 - May 2020

- Continuous Integration workflow
  - Created Gitlab CI/CD pipeline for testing REST API's product. It resulted in keeping Production branch clean.
  - CI/CD stages included:
    - Deploy GKE cluster, setup environment and health checks of cluster.
    - Deploy products on the cluster.
    - Health checks of cluster including availability and accessibility
    - Functionality checks: Kubernetes Jobs for API testing written in Python scripts and provisioned by Ansible on the GKE cluster.
    - Cleanup cluster
- Chaos Engineering:
  - Created Gitlab Pipeline for Chaos Engineering E2E tests of product OpenEBS CStor
    Volumes
  - Deployed OpenEBS Control and Data Plane components with CStor (Containerized Attached Storage Pool)
  - Tests included:
    - App Based: Deploying of Stateful and Stateless workloads (like Busybox, Prometheus, Minio, Percona etc.) Liveness, Load Generation on the apps
    - Cluster Based:
      - Fault Tolerance i.e., Pod, Container, Node, Disk Failures etc.
      - Availability of volumes (Replication Factor)

- Worked on Data Migration As A Service using OpenEBS Velero Plugin stored on AWS S3 Buckets, Google Cloud, Minio etc.
- Worked on Dynamic Provisioning of Kubernetes Local PV
  - Talk selected on Cloud Native Rejects "Building Blocks: Dynamic provisioning of Kubernetes Local PV"

Celebal Technologies, Jaipur - Associate Data Engineer

Sept 2017 - Sept 2018

- Worked on a full stack Data ETL and reporting project for a leading media networks client on Azure Cloud including a variety of technologies i.e., Azure Data Factory and SSIS as ETL platform, Azure Blob Storage as the storage platform, Azure HDInsight and Azure SQL Data Warehouse as Data processing/transforming platform and finally Power BI as the reporting tool.
- Worked in a Data Orchestration project for a leading automotive corporation client involving
   Azure Data factory as ETL tool, Azure Data Lake Store as storage platform and Azure Data Lake
   Analytics as processing platform through U-SQL.

#### **TALKS**

- Preserve Kubernetes state using velero
- Run ZFS in userspace
- Cloud Native Rejects "Building Blocks: Dynamic provisioning of Kubernetes Local PV"
- Migrating stateful apps running on Kubernetes

# **SKILLS**

- Cloud Native: Kubernetes, Docker
- Programming Languages: Golang, Python, Bash
- Tools: Ansible, VMware Velero
- Others: Github, GCP, Linux Internals

#### Education

2014 - 2018

Jaipur Engineering College & Research Center, Jaipur - B. Tech, Computer Science

## **Contact Details**

Email Id: harshita.sharma6174@gmail.com

Cell Number: +91-8561896064